Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Diamond Information Center Vertical File, 1930s-1980s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Diamond Information Center Vertical File 1930s-1980s
J. Walter Thompson Company. Diamond Information Center.
34.5 linear feet Extent: About 31,050 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
The J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT), founded in 1864, is one of the largest and oldest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The Diamond Information Center (DIC) operates as the public relations division of the diamond marketing group at J. Walter Thompson on behalf of De Beers Consolidated Mines, Ltd. The Diamond Information Center Vertical File spans the years from the 1930s to the 1980s and is chiefly an informational file of printed materials. The file was originally created when the N.W. Ayers advertising agency handled the De Beers account. The vertical file was transferred to JWT along with the account. JWT currently handles the advertising for De Beers diamonds. The file is organized into numbered, topical sections that cover a broad range of subjects relating to diamonds, the diamond industry, and the fashion design industry. Topics include: famous diamonds; the annual Diamonds International Awards; diamonds, diamond mining and trade in Africa (especially Angola and South Africa), Brazil, India, Russia and the United States; the analysis, classification, grading and cutting of gem-quality and industrial diamonds; public and private collectors, collections and exhibitions of diamonds, gems, precious stones and jewelry, including the crown jewels of European (particularly Great Britain), Russian and Indian monarchies; the history, advertising and marketing of diamonds, gems, precious stones and jewelry; the manufacture and mechanical properties of artificial diamonds and other precious stones; and the history, cultural and social aspects of the clothing and fashion design industry, with folders on individual designers, merchandisers, and fashion shows.
RL.00684
Language: Material in English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Diamond Information Center Vertical File was transferred to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from the J. Walter Thompson Company in 1998.
Historical Note
The J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT), founded in 1864, is one of the largest and oldest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The Diamond Information Center (DIC) operates as the public relations division of the diamond marketing group at J. Walter Thompson on behalf of De Beers Consolidated Mines, Ltd.
Collection Overview
The Diamond Information Center Vertical File spans the years from the 1930s to the 1980s and is chiefly an informational file of printed materials. The file was originally created when the N.W. Ayers advertising agency handled the De Beers account. The vertical file was transferred to JWT along with the account. JWT currently handles the advertising for De Beers diamonds.
The file is organized into numbered, topical sections that cover a broad range of subjects relating to diamonds, the diamond industry, and the fashion design industry. The numbered subjects reflect the original classification schema used by the Diamond Information Center. Some high-level subjects have been added to improve readability; these have been inserted within brackets, and follow the numerical pattern previously established by the Center. Topics include: famous diamonds; the annual Diamond International Awards; diamonds, diamond mining and trade in Africa (especially Angola and South Africa), Brazil, India, Russia and the United States; the analysis, classification, grading and cutting of gem-quality and industrial diamonds; public and private collectors, collections and exhibitions of diamonds, gems, precious stones and jewelry, including the crown jewels of European (particularly Great Britain), Russian and Indian monarchies; the history, advertising and marketing of diamonds, gems, precious stones and jewelry; the manufacture and mechanical properties of artificial diamonds and other artificial precious stones; and the history, cultural and social aspects of the clothing and fashion design industry, with folders on individual designers, merchandisers, and fashion shows.
Subject Headings
J. Walter Thompson Company; De Beers Consolidated Mines; Diamonds International Awards; Advertising -- History; Advertising -- Research; Crown jewels; Crown jewels -- Great Britain; Diamond industry and trade; Diamond industry and trade -- South Africa; Diamond jewelry -- History; Diamond mines and mining; Diamond mines and mining -- South Africa; Diamonds; Diamonds -- Africa; Diamonds -- Analysis; Diamonds, Artificial; Diamonds -- Brazil; Diamonds -- Classification; Diamonds -- Collectors and collecting; Diamonds -- Cutting; Diamonds -- Grading; Diamonds -- History -- Exhibitions; Diamonds -- India; Diamonds -- Industrial; Diamonds -- Russia (Federation); Diamonds -- South Africa; Fashion design -- History -- 20th century; Fashion designers -- History -- 20th century; Gems -- Collectors and collecting; Gems -- Marketing; Advertising -- Jewelry; Jewelry -- Collectors and collecting; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of the Collection
- Vertical File, (78 boxes)
  Note: Files are arranged numerically by code assigned to each topic by the JWT Diamond Information Center, except where noted.
  - [100. Diamond Jewelry]
    - 100. Diamond Jewelry (Box 1)
    - 110.ELL. Elle Encyclopedia: December 1969: Les Bijoux: reves, amours et drames (Box 1)
    - 110. Women's Jewelry
      - 111.AUC. Auctions of diamond jewelry (Box 1)
      - 111. Rings
        - 111.1. Hands (Box 1)
        - 111.1. Etiquette regarding engagement and wedding (Box 1)
        - 111.1. Symbolism (Box 1)
        - 111.1.GUA. Guards for rings (Box 1)
        - 111.1.GUIL. Ring Guild of America (Box 1)
        - 111.1. Photos of rings (Box 1)
        - 111.1.1. Eternity rings (Box 1)
        - 111.1.1. Signet (Box 1)
        - 111.1.2. Engagement ring mountings (Box 1)
        - 111.1.2. Engagement or keeper rings
          - 111.1.2.1.0.HIS. History of the engagement ring (Box 1)
          - 111.1.2.1.0.STY. Styles of engagement rings (Box 2)
        - 111.1.2.CEL. Engagement rings of celebrities (Box 2)
        - 111.1.2.1. Solitaires
          - 111.1.2.1.1. Brilliant cut (Box 2)
          - 111.1.2.1.2. Emerald cut (Box 2)
          - 111.1.2.1.3. Marquise cut (Box 2)
          - 111.1.2.1.4. Oval cut (Box 2)
          - 111.1.2.1.6. Heart shaped (Box 2)
          - 111.1.2.2.1. Cluster rings (Box 2)
          - 111.1.2.2.2. Illusion setting (Box 2)
          - 111.1.2.2.3. Pear shaped (Box 2)
          - 111.1.2.2.3. Wide band (Box 2)
        - 111.1.3. Wedding rings (Box 2)
        - 111.1.3. Wedding rings used in war (Box 2)
        - 111.1.3.WID. Widow's rings (Box 2)
        - 111.1.4. Matched sets (Box 2)
        - 111.1.4.LOC. Locked rings (Box 2)
        - 111.1.5. Friendship rings (Box 2)
        - 111.1.6. Anniversary rings (Box 2)
      - 111.2. Brooches, Pins, and Clips
        - 111.2.2. Brooches and clips (Box 3)
      - 111.3. Earrings
        - 111.3. Earring, photos (Box 3)
      - 111.4. Necklaces
        - 111.4.2. Necklaces (Box 3)
        - 111.4.3. Pendants (Box 3)
        - 111.4.4. Collars (Box 4)
      - 111.5. Bracelets
        - 111.5.2. Bracelets (Box 4)
        - 111.5.2. Bracelets, photos (Box 4)
        - 111.5.4. Hand ornaments (Box 4)
      - 111.6. Watches
        - 111.6.1. Watches (Box 4)
        - 111.6.GUB. Gubelin watches (Box 4)
        - 111.6.2. Watches, photos (Box 4)
      - [111.7. Tiaras and Hair Ornaments]
        - 111.7. Hair ornaments (Box 4)
        - 111.7.5. Ferroniere (Box 4)
        - 111.7. Tiaras (Box 5)
      - 111.8. Miscellaneous Jewelry
        - 111.8.PAT. Patek Phillipe's reinvention of jewelry (Box 5)
        - 111.8.2. Belts (jeweled) (Box 5)
        - 111.8.3. Monogram jewelry (Box 5)
        - 111.9. Military Jewelry
          - 111.9.1M Military jewelry, photos (Box 5)
        - 111.9.2. Add-to-jewelry (Box 5)
        - 111.9.3. Charms (Box 5)
        - 111.9.4. Floral jewelry (Box 5)
    - [112. Men's Jewelry]
      - 112.1. Rings (Box 5)
      - 112.2. Cuff links for men (Box 6)
      - 112.5. Men's jewelry (Box 6)
      - 112.6. Other (Box 6)
      - 112.7. The Diamond Eaters (Box 6)
      - 112.8. Sources (Box 6)
      - 112.9. Fashions (Box 6)
      - 112.10.1. Releases (Box 6)
      - 112.10.2. Releases (Box 6)
      - 112.11. Research (Box 6)
    - [113. Crowns, Swords, Religious and Ceremonial Jewelry]
      - 113.1. Crowns (Box 7)
      - 113.1.GRB. Crowns of Great Britain (Box 7)
      - 113.2. Swords (Box 7)
      - 113.4.REL. Religious jewelry (Box 7)
      - 113.5.MOO. Moon plaque (ceremonial jewelry) (Box 7)
    - 118.4.ADO. Body adornment (Box 7)
    - 121. Style Trends (Box 7)
    - 121.0. World history of jewelry
      - 121.1. Ancient beliefs about jewelry (Box 7)
      - 121.2. Medieval jewelry (Box 7)
      - 121.3. Renaissance jewelry (Box 7)
      - 121.4. 16th century jewelry (Box 7)
      - 121.6. 18th century jewelry (Box 7)
      - 121.7. 19th century jewelry
        - 121.7. Edwardian (Box 7)
        - 121.7. Victorian (Box 7)
      - 121.8.A. Art objects made into modern jewelry (Box 8)
      - 121.8.A. Animal jewelry (1960s) (Box 8)
      - 121.8.ANT. Antique jewelry (Box 8)
      - 121.8.BIR. Bird and animal jewelry (Box 8)
      - 121.8.MER. Merry widow mounting (Box 8)
    - [122. Jewelry Traditions]
      - 122. Jewelry traditions, 1900-1929 (Box 8)
      - 122. Jewelry traditions of the 1930s (Box 8)
      - 122. Jewelry traditions of the 1940s (Box 8)
      - 122. Jewelry traditions of the 1950s, (1-2 of 3 folders) (Box 8)
      - 122. Jewelry traditions of the 1950s, (3 of 3 folders) (Box 9)
      - 122. Jewelry traditions of the 1960s (Box 9)
    - 122.1.BRO. Broken engagements (Box 9)
    - 122.1.ES. Engagement status (1959 study) (Box 9)
    - 122.2.STA. Marriage statistics (Box 9)
    - 123. Gifts of jewels
      - 123. Gift occasion: Mother's Day (Box 9)
    - 130. Fancy Fever article, Modern Jeweler, 1984 (Box 9)
    - [131. Crown Jewels]
      - 131.1.1. Crown jewels (general) (Box 9)
      - 131.1.2. European crown jewls (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
      - 131.1.4. Crown of the Andes (Box 9)
      - 131.1.1.TAV. Jean Baptiste Tavernier (Box 9)
      - 131.1.3.IND. India-Mogul emperors (Box 9)
      - 131.2.1. Crown jewels of Austria-Hungary (Box 9)
      - 131.2.2. Denmark--crown jewels (Box 9)
      - 131.2.3. French crown jewels (Box 10)
      - 131.2.4. Crown jewels of Great Britain (descriptive)
        - 131.2.4.GRE. Crown jewels of Great Britain (photos) (Box 10)
        - 131.2.4.MAR. Queen Mary--crown jewels, etc. (Box 10)
        - 131.2.4. Crown jewels/Princess Di (Box 10)
        - 131.2.4. Great Britain, Charles, Prince of Wales-Coronet for Investiture, July 1969 (Box 10)
        - 131.2.4. Tower of London (crown jewels) (Box 10)
      - 131.2.5. Iranian crown jewels (Box 10)
      - 131.2.6. Italy--crown jewels--House of Savoy (Box 10)
      - 131.2.9. Russian crown jewels, (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - 131.2.11. Swedish crown jewels (Box 11)
      - 131.2.12. Crown jewels of India (Box 11)
    - 132. Queens and Royalty
      - 132.1.1Z. Queen Zenobia (Box 11)
      - 132.2. Royal Pieces and Collections
        Arranged by names of countries and rulers.
        - 132.2.1. Geraldine of Albania (Box 11)
        - 132.2.2.MAR. Maria Theresa (Box 11)
        - 132.2.2E. Elizabeth of Austria (Box 11)
        - 132.2.3. Belgium royalty (Box 11)
        - 132.2.4. Royal family of Denmark (Box 11)
        - [132.5. France]
          - 132.2.5.E. Eugenie of France (Box 11)
          - 132.2.5.F. Royal Families of France (Box 11)
          - 132.2.5.J. Josephine of France (Box 11)
          - 132.2.5.LOUIX. Louis IX, King of France (Box 11)
          - 132.2.5.5L,XIV. Louis XIV of France (Box 11)
          - 132.2.5.5L,XV. Louis XV of France (Box 11)
          - 132.2.5L. Mary Louise of France (Box 11)
          - 123.2.5.MAR. Marie Antoinette, Queen of France (Box 11)
          - 132.2.5.MAR. Marie Antoinette necklace (Box 12)
          - 132.2.5.M. Medici Family as French royalty (Box 12)
          - 132.2.5.N. Napoleon's family (Box 12)
          - 132.2.5.SOR. Agnes Sorel (Box 12)
        - [132.2.6. Great Britain]
          - 132.2.6.ALE. Alexandra, Queen of England (Box 12)
          - 132.2.6.ALEX. Alexandra (Princesses and Queen) (Box 12)
          - 132.2.6.ANN. Princess Anne (Box 12)
          - 132.2.6.BRI. British brides--wedding gifts and customs (Box 12)
          - 132.2.6. Charles (Prince, son of Elizabeth II) (Box 12)
          - 132.2.6. Duchess of Kent (Marina and Katharine) (Box 12)
          - 132.2.6. Duchess of Windsor (Box 12)
          - 132.2.6. Edwardians (Box 12)
          - 132.2.6. Queen Elizabeth I (Box 12)
          - 132.2.6. Elizabeth II, Queen Mother of England
            - 132.2.6. Queen Elizabeth II jewelry--general (Box 13)
            - 132.2.6.ELI. Elizabeth II, Queen of England--badges (Box 13)
            - 132.2.6.ELI. Elizabeth II, Queen of England--bracelets (Box 13)
            - 132.2.6.ELI. Elizabeth II, Queen of England--brooches (Box 13)
            - 132.2.6. Coronation of Elizabeth II ( 1953), (3 folders) (Box 13)
            - 132.2.6.ELI. Queen Elizabeth II of England--diamond presentation, 21st birthday (Box 13)
            - 132.2.6.ELI. Elizabeth II, Queen of England--earrings (Box 13)
            - 132.2.6. Elizabeth II--life and reign (Box 14)
            - 132.2.6.ELI. Elizabeth II, Queen of England--necklaces (Box 14)
            - 132.2.6.ELI. Elizabeth II, Queen of England--portrait photos (Box 14)
            - 132.2.6.ELI. Elizabeth II, Queen of England--stomachers (Box 14)
            - 132.2.6.ELI. Elizabeth II, Queen of England--tiaras (Box 14)
            - 132.2.6. Elizabeth II--Tours and jewels she wears on them--Australia (Box 14)
            - 132.2.6. Elizabeth II--Tours--Canada, New York, Williamsburg (1957) (Box 14)
            - 132.2.6. Elizabeth II--Tours--France (1957) (Box 15)
            - 132.2.6. Elizabeth II--Tours--India, Iran, Pakistan (Box 15)
            - 132.2.6. Elizabeth II--Tours--South Africa (1947) (Box 15)
            - 132.2.6.ELI. Elizabeth II, Queen of England--watches (Box 15)
            - 132.2.6.ELI. Elizabeth II, Queen of England--wedding and wedding gifts (Box 15)
          - 132.2.6.GEO. Georgian Kings of England (Box 15)
          - 132.2.6.GEO. George VI--coronation (Box 15)
          - 132.2.6.HEN. Henry VIII (Box 15)
          - 132.2.6.MAR. Princess Margaret (Box 15)
          - 132.2.6.MAR. Queen Mary of England (Box 15)
          - 132.2.6. Queens, British royalty (Box 15)
          - 132.2.6.RF. British Royal Family relatives (Box 16)
          - 132.2.6. Victoria and Albert Museum (Box 16)
          - 132.2.6.VIC. Victoria, Queen of England (Box 16)
        - [132.2.7. Greece]
          - 132.2.7. Anne Marie, Queen of Greece (Box 16)
          - 132.2.7F. Frederika, Queen of Greece (Box 16)
        - 132.2.8. Hawaiian Royalty (Box 16)
        - [132.2.9. India]
          - 132.2.9. Indian Princes (Box 16)
          - 132.2.9S. Shah Jehan and Taj Mahal (Box 16)
        - 132.2.10. Iranian Royalty (Box 16)
        - 132.2.26. Medici Family in Italy (Box 16)
        - 132.2.11. Japanese Royalty (Box 16)
        - 132.2.15. Mary of Burgundy (Luxembourg) (Box 16)
        - 132.2.12. Princess Grace of Monaco (Box 16)
        - 132.3.13. Nepalese Royalty (Box 16)
        - 132.2.14. Netherlands Royalty (Box 16)
        - 132.2.23. [Persia] Aga Khan and Family (Box 16)
        - 132.2.30. Poland--crown and crown of Madonna (Box 16)
        - 132.2.28. Portugal (Box 16)
        - 132.2.16. Prussian Royalty (Box 16)
        - [132.2.24. Russia]
          - 132.2.24. Catherine the Great, Empress of Russia (Box 17)
          - 132.2.24. Russian Royalty (Box 17)
        - 132.2.27. Roumanian Royalty (Box 17)
        - 132.2.29. Jewels of Saxony (Box 17)
        - 132.2.20. Scandinavian Royalty (Box 17)
        - [132.2.17. Scotland]
          - 132.2.17. Scotland (Box 17)
          - 132.2.17. Mary Queen of Scots (Box 17)
        - 132.2.18. Sikkim Royalty (Box 17)
        - [132.2.19. Spain]
          - 132.2.19G. Spanish Royalty (general) (Box 17)
          - 132.2.19I. Isabella of Spain (Box 17)
        - 132.2.21. Thailand Royalty (Box 17)
        - 132.2.22. Queen of Tonga (Box 17)
        - 132.2.28. Turkey .. Topkapi Palace, Istanbul (Box 17)
    - [133-134. United States]
      - 133. First Ladies' jewelry (Box 17)
      - 133.COO. Coolidge Diamonds (Box 17)
      - 134. White House jewelry (Box 17)
    - 140. Museum and Public Collections
      - 140.BOS. Boston Museum of Fine Arts (Box 17)
      - 140.CHI. Chicago Natural History Museum (Box 17)
      - 140.CNY. City of New York Museum, old gown photos (Box 17)
      - 140.F. Faberge Easter Eggs (Box 17)
      - 140.FIN. Finch College Art Museum's International Jewelry Collection (Box 17)
      - 140.HAR. Harvard University Mineral Collection (Box 17)
      - 140.MET,NYC. Metropolitan Museum, NYC (Box 17)
      - 140.LOU. Museum + Public Collections: Louvre, Paris (Box 17)
      - 140.MUN. Munich Royal Residence, treasury in .., (2 folders) (Box 17)
      - 140. National Estate Presentations, Inc. Collection (Box 17)
      - 140.NY. The World of Gems - New York State Museum Exhibition (Box 17)
      - 140.ROM. Royal Ontario Museum (Box 18)
      - 140.SMI. Smithsonian Institute, gem and jewelry (Box 18)
      - 140. University of Pennsylvania .. Evans Collection (Box 18)
      - 140.VAT. Vatican Museum (Box 18)
    - 141. Diamonds in the arts (Box 18)
    - 150. Private and Individual Pieces and Collections
      Arranged alphabetically by person or collection.
      - 150.PRI. Private and individual collections (Box 18)
      - 150.A-F. Personalities, miscellaneous (A-F) (Box 18)
      - 150.AG. Astors & Goulds (Box 18)
      - 150.ALL. Gracie Allen (Box 18)
      - 150.ALP. Mme. Herve Alphand (Box 18)
      - 150.ARD. Elizabeth Arden (Box 18)
      - 150.BEA. Cecil Beaton (Box 19)
      - 150.BEN. Constance Bennett (Box 19)
      - 150.BER. Sarah Bernhardt (Box 19)
      - 150.BLY. Ann Blyth (Box 19)
      - 150.BRA. Mrs. Omar Bradley (Box 19)
      - 150.BRA. Diamond Jim Brady (Box 19)
      - 150.BUF. Buffalo Bill (Box 19)
      - 150.CAF. Gwen Cafritz (Box 19)
      - 150.CRA. Joan Crawford (Box 19)
      - 150.DAC. Lily Dache (Box 19)
      - 150.DAH. Arlene Dahl (Box 19)
      - 150.DAV. Marion Davies (Box 19)
      - 150.EIS. Mamie Eisenhower (Box 19)
      - 150.FAR. Geraldine Farrar (Box 19)
      - 150.FOR. Mrs. Henry Ford, II (Box 19)
      - 150.FRA. Arlene Francis (Box 19)
      - 150.FRA. Brenda Frazier (Box 19)
      - 150.G-L. Personalities, miscellaneous (G-L) (Box 19)
      - 150.GAB. Gabor Sisters (Box 19)
      - 150.GAR. Mrs. Jack Gardner (Box 19)
      - 150.GOD. Paulette Goddard (Box 19)
      - 150.HAM. Lady Emma Hamilton (Box 19)
      - 150.HAR. Lady Pamela Harlech (Box 19)
      - 150.HEN. Sonja Henie (Box 19)
      - 150.JOH. Mrs. Lyndon Johnson and daughters (Box 19)
      - 150.KEN. Mrs. Edward Kennedy (Box 19)
      - 150.KHR. Mme. Khruschev and daughters (Box 19)
      - 150.LAF. Lafayette (Box 19)
      - 150.LAN. Lily Langtry (Box 19)
      - 150.LAW. Gertrude Lawrence (Box 19)
      - 150.LES. Mrs. Frank Leslie (Box 19)
      - 150.LIN. Mary Todd Lincoln (Box 19)
      - 150.LIN. Jenny Lind (Box 19)
      - 150.LUC. Clare Booth Luce (Box 19)
      - 150.M-R. Personalities, miscellaneous (M-R) (Box 19)
      - 150.McC. John McCormack (Box 19)
      - 150. McCullagh, Eveline (Box 19)
      - 150.MAH. Maharaja Runjit Singh, Ruler of Punjab, 1791-1839 (Box 19)
      - 150.MAR. Mary Martin (Box 19)
      - 150.MEL. Nellie Melba (Box 19)
      - 150.NEL. Lord Nelson (Box 19)
      - 150.NIX. Mrs. Richard Nixon and daughter (Box 20)
      - 150.OBE. Merle Oberon (Box 20)
      - 150.ONA. Jacqueline Onassis (Box 20)
      - 150.OPE. Opera singers (general) (Box 20)
      - 150.OTE. La Belle Otero (Box 20)
      - 150.PAL. Mrs. Potter Palmer (Box 20)
      - 150.PAT. Adeline Patti (Box 20)
      - 150.PER. Eva Peron (Box 20)
      - 150.POS. Marjorie Merriweather Post (Box 20)
      - 150. Private Collections of Americans (Box 20)
      - 150.Q. Queen of Diamonds (Box 20)
      - 150.RHO. Cecil Rhodes (Box 20)
      - 150.ROC. Rockefellers (Box 20)
      - 150.ROO. Roosevelts (Box 20)
      - 150.RUB. Helena Rubinstein (Box 20)
      - 150.RUS. Lillian Russell (Box 20)
      - 150.RUS. Rosalind Russell (Box 20)
      - 150.S-Z. Personalities, miscellaneous (S-Z) (Box 20)
      - 150.SAB. Sabine Heritage Collection (Box 20)
      - 150.SHE. Norma Shearer (Box 20)
      - 150.SIN. Nancy Sinatra, Jr. (Box 20)
      - 150.SOR. Ex-Queen Soraya (Box 20)
      - 150.STA. Henry Morton Stanley (Box 20)
      - 150.STE. Rise Stevens (Box 20)
      - 150.SWA. Gloria Swanson (Box 20)
      - 150.SWA. Gladys Swarthout (Box 20)
      - 150.TAB. Baby Doe Tabor (Box 20)
      - 150.TAV. Jean Baptiste Tavernier (Box 20)
      - 150.TAY. Elizabeth Taylor (Burton) (Box 20)
      - 150.THU. Tom Thumb and wife (Box 20)
      - 150.TRU. Trumans (Box 20)
      - 150.TWA. Mark Twain (Box 20)
      - 150.VAN. The Vanderbilts (Box 21)
      - 150.WAG. Mrs. Robert Wagner (Box 21)
      - 150.WHI. Mrs. C.V. Whitney (Box 21)
      - 150.WIL. Dr. John Williamson (Box 21)
      - 150.YOU. Loretta Young (Box 21)
    - [160. References for General Information on Famous and Large Diamonds]
      - 160.ALPHA. Alphabetical lists of diamonds (Box 21)
      - 160. Famous diamonds [general information] (Box 21)
      - 161.AME. American discovered diamonds (Box 21)
      - 161.BAU. Baumgold Collection (Box 21)
      - 161.CAM. Cambridge Diamond (Box 21)
      - 161.CHA. Charts for Notable Diamonds of the World (Box 21)
      - 161.COR. Correspondence for Notable Diamonds of the World, (2 folders) (Box 21)
      - 161.COR. Correspondence for Notable Diamonds of the World, contined (Box 21)
      - 161.ENCY. Encyclopedia, famous diamonds (Box 21)
      - 161.FDP. Famous diamonds: black-and-white photos (Box 22)
      - 161. Large diamonds (Box 22)
      - 161.MIS. Miscellaneous famous diamonds (Box 22)
      - 161.MIS. Miscellaneous for Notable Diamonds of the World, (2 folders) (Box 22)
      - 161.HIS. Histories of famous diamonds (Box 22)
      - 161.OWN. Owned in the United States (Box 22)
      - 161.WIN. Winston Stones (Box 22)
        See ARCOTS under A's; See WESTMINSTER tiara behind the TIARA folder in JEWELRY
      - 161.1 Replicas of famous diamonds, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 22)
      - 161.1 Replicas of famous diamonds, (2 of 2 folders) (Box 23)
    - [162. Famous Diamonds (Individual)]
      Arranged alphabetically.
      - 162.A. Arcot Diamonds (Box 23)
      - 162.AGR. Agra Diamond (Box 23)
      - 162.AKB. Akbar Shah Diamond (Box 23)
      - 162.ALG. Algeiba Star (Box 23)
      - 162.ALK. Alkaid Star (Box 23)
      - 162.ALS. Al Shams Diamond (Box 23)
      - 162.AME. American Women who Own Diamonds (Box 23)
      - 162.A. Arkansas diamonds (Box 23)
      - 162.ASH. Ashberg Diamond (Box 23)
      - 162.AUS. Australian diamonds (Box 23)